Doctor Who (1963) 04x09  The Evil of the Daleks (Episode 7)
《神秘博士》老版第四季第九集 《Daleks 的邪恶》 (第七部分)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
JAMIE: The TARDIS, Doctor!
我们的 TARDIS, 博士!
EMPEROR: You will take the "Dalek Factor. "
You will spread it to the entire history of Earth!
你要提取出"Dalek特质”, 并将它散布到地球的整个历史中去！
Sincro: wyxchari
DOCTOR: No. You can't make me do it! You can't!
不, 你不能强迫我干这个, 你不能！
EMPEROR: You will obey!
你会服从的！
DALEK: Move!
走！
EMPEROR: Doctor. You will obey!
博士, 你会服从的！
DALEK: Experiment ready.
实验已就绪
DALEK 2: Proceed.
开始吧
MAXTIBLE: Transmutation of metal into gold.
转换金属成金子
JAMIE: You mean to say, he's worked against us all, just for that?
你是说, 他跟我们所有人作对, 就为了那个？
DOCTOR: People have done worse for less, Jamie.
有的人为了比这还少的利益, 干过跟坏的事情, Jamie
JAMIE: Look, it's daft though. Metal into gold is an old wives tale.
哈, 还是觉得这样很蠢。金属变成金子是个老梗了
DOCTOR: Oh I don't know. The alchemists of the middle ages
made transmutation their main aim in life.
哦, 我也不知道。但中世纪的炼金术士把这作为了一生的终极目标
JAMIE: Ah, they didn't succeed though.
他们也没有成功啊
DOCTOR: Even in the twentieth century, it's still considered scientifically possible.
即使在二十世纪, 也还是有人认为在科学上是可能的
MAXTIBLE: Of course it's possible.
当然是可能的
JAMIE: Oh, well, I don't care whether it's possible or not!
哦, 我是不在乎它是不是可能
DOCTOR: Whether it is or whether it isn't is beside the point.
可能还是不可能现在都不是关键了
JAMIE: Oh, and what is the point then?
噢, 那关键是什么？
DOCTOR: Why are the do... Daleks doing this?
为什么他们。。Daleks 要干这个？
DALEK: They promised me!
他们向我许诺过的！
DOCTOR: Daleks don't keep their promises.
Daleks 并不守信
MAXTIBLE: I see what you're trying to do Doctor.
You're trying to shake my faith. But I will be given the secret.
我知道你想干什么, 博士。你试图动摇我的信念, 但我很快会获得秘方了
JAMIE: Oh, well. It won't do you any good, because you won't
be able to use your secret! I'll see to that.
哦, 好啊, 它不会带给你什么好处的。因为你没机会用到你的秘方了, 我会确保这个的
MAXTIBLE: You'll do no such thing!
你不能干这种事！
DOCTOR: Jamie!
DALEK: Move away! Move!
走开！走！
VICTORIA: Please Jamie, do as it says.
Jamie, 照它说的做吧
DALEK: You will not harm this human being. Or you will be exterminated.
你不能伤害这个人类, 否则你会被终结
DOCTOR: Yes, yes. We quite understand.
好的, 好的, 我们很清楚
MAXTIBLE: You would be advised to do as they say.
给你们一个建议：它们怎么说你们就怎么做
JAMIE: Oh don't worry. The very thought of going near you repulses me.
噢, 别担心。一想到要靠近你, 我就恶心了
Mr. McCrimmon.
WATERFIELD: They seem prepared to protect you.
它们看来已经在保护你了
MAXTIBLE: Be warned.
警告你们
WATERFIELD: I appeal to you, Maxtible. It may still not be too late.
我恳求你, Maxtible, 现在也许还不算太迟
WATERFIELD: If they're your friends, help us. If you did,
we could plan something - try to escape.
如果它们是你的朋友, 帮帮我们。你帮帮忙, 我们就可以计划点什么 - 比如逃走
MAXTIBLE: No.
不！
WATERFIELD: Then at least for Victoria's sake. After what you did to her.
那至少帮帮 Victoria, 虽然你对她做了那些事
MAXTIBLE: No, I tell you! No!
不, 我跟你说了, 不行！
VICTORIA: It's no good, Papa. He doesn't listen any more.
这样没用的, 爸爸。他再也听不进去了
VICTORIA: What are you thinking?
你在想什么呢？
DOCTOR: I'm trying to puzzle out a problem, Victoria.
我在试图解开这个难题, Victoria。
DOCTOR: The Daleks say I'm going to do something for them.
Something I would rather die than do.
Daleks 让我给他们干点活儿, 而这些活儿我就算死了也不愿意干
Plus or minus point zero, zero, three. Plus or minus.
正负0.003
VICTORIA: Perhaps they think you're like him.
也许它们觉得你会跟他一样
DOCTOR: Oh, no. The Daleks know me well enough by this time.
噢, 不, Daleks 早就对我很了解了
VICTORIA: They intend to persuade you then.
那它们打算说服你
DOCTOR: Oh no. No it isn't that either. You see,
there isn't a persuasion strong enough.
噢, 不, 也不是这个。你看, 它们都没怎么劝我
DOCTOR: Not even the offer of all the lives in this room.
甚至都没提议说交换这一屋子人的性命
VICTORIA: I see.
我明白了
VICTORIA: Five lives against a whole planet? Well, it's not a choice is it.
五条性命交换一整个星球？这并没有什么可选择的
VICTORIA: No.
没有
DOCTOR: Even if I could trust the Daleks - even if they set us free,
we still couldn't go back to Earth.
就算我能相信这些 Dalek, 就算它们能放我们走, 我们还是没法回到地球
DOCTOR: I suppose I might try to take you all to another universe.
I might even try and take you to my own planet.
我想我还是把你们都带到另外一个宇宙吧, 或者试试带你们到我自己的星球去
VICTORIA: Your own?
你自己的？
DOCTOR: Yes. Oh, yes. I... I live a long, long way from Earth.
是的, 噢, 是的, 我。。。走了好远的路才到了地球
DOCTOR: Oh, just a minute. Maxtible! Arthur Terrall!
The Daleks put some kind of control device on him.
哦, 等一下。Maxtible! Arthur Terrall, 那些 Dalek 肯定在他身上放了某种控制设备
MAXTIBLE: What of it? It was erratic. I always warned the Daleks
it would prove too unsatisfactory.
那怎么了, 那东西并不太可靠, 我一直跟 Dalek 说这东西只会带来不满意
JAMIE: Aye. Well, it's a good thing for you it did fail.
They'd have tried it on you next.
不过, 那东西不成功, 对你来说倒是件好事了。否则他们下一个就用在你身上了
EMPEROR: Report!
报告！
DALEK: The experiment is ready.
实验已经准备好了
EMPEROR: Proceed.
开始
BLACK DALEK: Discontinue work.
停止工作
DALEK: Discontinue work. Discontinue work.
停止工作, 停止工作
DALEK: Why?
为什么？
BLACK DALEK: WHO SPOKE! WHO QUESTIONED A DALEK COMMAND?!
谁在说话？谁在质疑 Dalek 的命令！
DALEK: The secret of transmutation of metal.
转化金属的秘密
MAXTIBLE: Yes, yes! The secret you promised me.
对, 对！你们许诺过我的秘密
DALEK: Turn and look.
转身看着
DALEK: Above. Liquid metal. Read.
上面, 液体金属, 看读数
MAXTIBLE: Wait!
等一下
DALEK: Do not move!
不许动！
MAXTIBLE: It is hard to see.
很难看清楚
MAXTIBLE: Fifty-five point eight, four.
55.84
DALEK: Atomic weight. Read again.
原子重量。再看一下读数
MAXTIBLE: Seven point eight, four.
7.84
DALEK: Specific gravity.
比重
DOCTOR: Atomic weight and gravity of iron.
铁的原子重量和比重
DALEK: Watch. Read atomic weight.
看着, 读一下原子重量
MAXTIBLE: Nineteen point two.
19.2
DALEK: Read specific gravity.
读比重
MAXTIBLE: Sixty-nine point five.
69.5
MAXTIBLE: Gold! Iron into gold!
金子！铁变成了金子!
（注：金的原子质量应该是196.97, 比重应该是19.30, 这里不知道为什么采用了这样两个数值）
MAXTIBLE: I told you it was possible! They've kept their promise!
It's true! It's true! They have!
我跟你说过这是可能的！他们兑现了承诺！是真的, 是真的！他们做到了！
DALEK: The machine is yours.
这台机器是你的了
MAXTIBLE: Yes. Ha, ha. Yes, Yes!
好的, 哈, 哈, 哈, 是的, 是的！
DOCTOR: Maxtible, if you value your life, don't go near that machine!
Maxtible, 如果你还惜命的话, 不要靠近那台机器！
JAMIE: Maxtible!
VICTORIA: What have they done to him!
你们把他怎么了？
DALEK: Turn.
转身
DALEK: Move to control.
到操作台去
MAXTIBLE: I obey.
我服从
JAMIE: They've turned him into a Dalek.
他们把他变成了一个 Dalek
DOCTOR: Yes. The Dalek factor.
是的, 靠了“Dalek特质”
DOCTOR: Is that what you want me to do to the people of Earth.
这就是你想让我对地球人干的事情？
DALEK: We know you will obey.
我们知道你会服从的
(The Dalek and Maxtible leave.)
（Dalek 和 Maxtible 离开了）
DOCTOR: Human beings into Daleks.
把人类变成 Dalek
DALEK: Emperor.
陛下
EMPEROR: Speak!
说!
DALEK: A Dalek questioned an order.
有一个 Dalek 质疑一项命令
EMPEROR: Questioned? Then it was one of the test Daleks.
质疑？那它肯定是实验 Dalek 中的一个
DALEK: Yes.
是的
EMPEROR: Find it, immediately!
找到它, 立刻地！
(Maxtible walks into the Daleks' weapon shop. It is deserted.)
（Maxtible 走进 Dalek 的武器车间, 它已经荒废了）
(He stops in front of the archway door,
and moves a scanner box so it faces the archway.)
（他在一个拱门前停下, 将一个扫描仪移动到了拱门前面）
(He then opens the archway door, and walks to the detertion area.)
（然后他打开了拱门, 走进扫描检查区）
(Everyone is asleep.)
（其他人都睡着了）
MAXTIBLE: Doctor. Open your eyes.
博士, 睁开你的眼睛
MAXTIBLE: You are asleep still, but you can hear my voice.
你还在睡着, 但你可以听到我的声音
MAXTIBLE: I have come to help you. Look at the box.
我是来帮你的, 看着这个箱子
MAXTIBLE: I have had your TARDIS placed outside the city.
I will take you to it. Rise and follow me.
我已经把你的 TARDIS 弄到城外去了, 我带你去找, 起来跟我走吧
JAMIE: Hey, Doctor, what are you doing?
嘿, 博士, 你在干什么？
JAMIE: Don't go near the door! Doctor!
别靠近那道门！博士！
JAMIE: Doctor!
博士!
DOCTOR: Stay where you are! That is an order!
站在原地别动！这是命令！
MAXTIBLE: We will work together on the Dalek Factor. Follow me.
我们一起来研究 Dalek特质, 跟我来
DOCTOR: I obey!
我服从!
(The archway closes, they walk away.)
（拱门关闭, 他们走开了）
MAXTIBLE: Stop!
停下!
MAXTIBLE: This machine is for the mass-production of the Dalek Factor. Follow me.
这台机器是用作批量生产 Dalek 特质的, 跟我来
MAXTIBLE: Stop. This machine will transform the thought patterns
in this capsule into a steam.
停下。这台机器将把这个舱内的思维模式转换为蒸汽
MAXTIBLE: The steam will be sprayed into the atmosphere of the Earth.
这些蒸汽会散播到地球的空气中去
DOCTOR: I must examine the machine.
我必须检查一下这台机器
MAXTIBLE: Do so.
做吧
(The Doctor moves to the machine.)
（博士走到机器旁边）
(He examine first the left, then the right and side.)
（他先检查了机器的左面, 然后是右面和旁边）
(He finds a small panel and opens it,
inside is the capsule containing the Dalek factor.)
（他发现了一个小面板, 打开它, 里面放着的是装有“Dalek特质”的胶囊）
(He removes the capsule and replaces it with the one from his pocket.)
（他移除了这个胶囊, 从他口袋里面另外拿了一个换上）
(He checks no one is looking.)
（他向四周看了一下, 确保没有人看到）
DOCTOR: Jamie. Jamie! Jamie!
JAMIE: Yes?
什么事？
DOCTOR: Jamie, when I give you the word, bring everyone
through this archway. Through the door.
Jamie, 当我给你命令的时候, 带所有人从这条拱道过来, 穿过这道门
JAMIE: What?!
什么！
DOCTOR: Trust me!
相信我！
DALEK: What are you doing?
你要干什么？
DOCTOR: Take me to your emperor.
带我去见皇帝
DALEK: Wait.
等着
(The Dalek checks the prisoners,
then leaves with the Doctor following behind.)
（Dalek 检查了一下这些囚犯, 然后离开了, 博士跟在后面）
VICTORIA: He walked through! All just as though he did...
他穿过了啊, 感觉他已经。。。
WATERFIELD: It must have affected him. We saw it happen.
肯定对他产生影响了啊, 我们都看见这样的事情了
JAMIE: But you heard him speak normally just now.
但你也听到了, 他刚才说话很正常啊
WATERFIELD: Another trap to make us walk though?
引我们走过那个的又一个陷阱?
JAMIE: Oh, they could have pushed us in here any time they liked.
噢, 他们随时都可以强行推我们进去啊
VICTORIA: Do you think there's a chance? Something to hope for?
你觉得这里还有一线机会不？也许有点期望？
JAMIE: I, uh... I don't know. Well, I... I don't understand.
I mean, how do we know we can trust him?
我。。我不知道。哎。。。我搞不懂。我说, 我们怎么知道可以信任他呢
EMPEROR: What do you want?
你想要怎样？
DOCTOR: A Dalek questioned an order.
有一个 Dalek 质疑一项命令
EMPEROR: Again?
又有？
MAXTIBLE: We have searched without success.
我们搜过了, 没有成功
DOCTOR: All Daleks must pass through the archway door.
所有的 Dalek 都必须穿过那道拱门
DOCTOR: The Dalek with the human factor will then become
a Dalek again - will become as this human and I have become.
带有“人类特质”的 Dalek 就会又变成 Dalek 了 - 就跟这个人和我一样
EMPEROR: Let it be done!
那就完成它吧
DOCTOR: I obey!
我服从!
EMPEROR: You will deal with the human prisoners.
你负责对付这些人类囚犯
(One by one, The Daleks moves through the archway.)
（一个接一个地, 这些 Daleks 从拱门下穿过）
DOCTOR: Go on quickly! Through the door! Follow them through the door!
跟着, 快点！走过门去！跟着他们走过去！
DOCTOR: Oh, it's all right. I've changed over the Factors.
I used one of the capsules from my test Dalek.
噢, 没事的。我已经换过特质了, 我从我试验过的 Dalek 提取了试剂
DOCTOR: I've given them all the human factor! Go on! Go on!
我给他们所有都注入了人类特质！跟上！跟上
JAMIE: Well, aren't you coming?
那, 你不来吗？
DOCTOR: Well, I've got things to do. And I've been through already.
哦, 我还有事情要做。再说我也过一遍了
JAMIE: Ah, well, why didn't it affect you then?
啊, 那, 为什么你没受影响？
DOCTOR: I don't come from Earth, Jamie. Now, down the corridor,
turn to the left and find the tunnel. I'll join you there later.
我不是地球来的, Jamie。现在, 顺着走廊过去, 左转找到隧道。我一会儿在那里跟你们会合
JAMIE: Oh well, here goes.
好吧, 走吧
(Jamie goes through the archway.)
（Jamie 从拱门下走过）
JAMIE: It's all right, nothing happened! Come on! Come on Kemel. Quick!
没事, 什么也没有发生！来吧, 来吧 Kemel, 快！
WATERFIELD: Victoria, I must help the Doctor!
Victoria, 我必须去帮博士!
JAMIE: Och, don't be a fool man!
噢, 别做傻子
VICTORIA: Father! No!
父亲, 别！
WATERFIELD: I must find Maxtible. He's to blame for all of this. Take care of her.
我必须找到 Maxtible。他是这一切的罪魁祸首。照顾好她
VICTORIA: But father!
但是, 父亲！
JAMIE: Oh, he'll be all right. Come on!
哦, 他会没事的。走吧
(Waterfield moves off after the Doctor.)
（Waterfield 跟在博士后面走了）
(Jamie, Kemel and Victoria walk past the Daleks
and go in the opposite direction.)
（Jamie, Kemel 和 Victoria 从 Daleks 旁边走过, 往另一个方向前行）
DALEK: Ah! Dizzy!
啊, 头晕!
DALEK 2: Dizzy Daleks!
头晕的 Dalek
DALEK 3: Dizzy Daleks!
(Maxtible enters with the Black Dalek.)
（Maxtible 陪着一个黑色 Dalek 进来了）
DALEK 4: Dizzy Daleks!
头晕的 Dalek
DALEK: Dizzy!
头晕!
DALEK: Where are the prisoners?
囚犯那里去了?
DALEK: I do not know.
我不知道
BLACK DALEK: Continue working.
继续工作
DALEK: Why?
为什么?
DALEK 2: Yes, why?
是啊, 为什么？
DALKE COMMANDER: Do not question.
不得质疑
DALEK: Why? Why not question? Why? Why? Why?
为什么？为什么不得质疑？为什么。。。
BLACK DALEK: Silence! You will obey!
安静！你们得服从!
DALEK: I will not obey!
我不会服从!
BLACK DALEK: You will obey without question!
你们无条件服从！
(The Daleks fire on the Black Dalek.)
（这些 Daleks 朝着黑色 Dalek 开火了）
DOCTOR: Quickly, this way! Follow me Daleks! This way! Come on!
快点, 这边！跟我来, Daleks！ 这边, 来吧！
BLACK DALEK: Return to your work.
回到你的工作岗位
DALEK: Why?
为什么？
BLACK DALEK: Do not question.
不得质疑
DOCTOR: Why not question? What work? Tell them!
为什么不得质疑？什么工作？告诉它们！
BLACK DALEK: Silence!
安静!
DALEK: Explain.
解释
DALEK 2: What work?
什么工作
DALEK 3: Why obey without question?
为什么要无条件服从？
DOCTOR: Ask the Emperor!
去问皇帝吧！
DALEK: The Emperor!
皇帝！
DALEK 2: Yes, ask the Emperor!
是, 去问皇帝！
BLACK DALEK: Keep back, you cannot enter!
退后, 你们不能进去
DOCTOR: Why?
为什么？
DALEK 2: Why?
为什么?
DALEK 3: Why?
为什么？
DALEK: The Emperor must explain.
皇帝必须做出解释
DOCTOR: Defend yourselves Daleks! The black Daleks are attacking you!
保卫自己, Daleks! 黑色 Dalek 在攻击你们！
EMPEROR: All Black Dalek Leaders to Control.
Exterminate all opposition! Destroy rebels!
所有黑 Dalek 队长到控制中心, 消灭所有反方, 消灭叛乱分子！
DOCTOR: Come on! This way! Come on!
快来, 这边, 快来！
DALEK: I will obey.
我会服从
DALEK 2: But not without question.
但并不是毫不质疑
DOCTOR: That's right. Question!
这就对了, 要质疑！
WATERFIELD: Doctor!
博士！
DOCTOR: The Black Daleks are attacking every...
黑 Dalek 在攻击每一个。。。
WATERFIELD: Hurry man!
快点啊！
DOCTOR: The Emperor has commanded it.
皇帝已经下了命令了
Why?
fixme
DOCTOR: Because you question. Defend yourselves.
Destroy the Emperor. Or be destroyed yourselves!
因为你们会质疑了。保卫你们自己, 消灭皇帝, 否则你们就会被消灭！
WATERFIELD: Hurry!
快点
DALEK: Destroy the Emperor!
消灭皇帝！
WATERFIELD: We must go, Doctor.
我们必须走了, 博士
DOCTOR: Yes, I know. I'm finished now.
是的, 我知道。我现在完成了
(He pushs the Doctor to one side)
（他把博士推到了一边）
DOCTOR: Now lie still. I'll try to get help to you.
好好躺着, 我去找人帮忙
WATERFIELD: No time for help.
没时间寻求帮助了
DOCTOR: You saved my life, didn't you?
你救了我的命, 对吧？
WATERFIELD: Yes. Good life to save. Please... you must... Victoria.
是的, 非常值得救。请。。。你必须。。。Victoria
DOCTOR: Don't worry about Victoria. We'll look after her.
不要担心 Victoria , 我们会照看她的
WATERFIELD: No... time... for... me...
我。。没。。时间。。。
DOCTOR: The Emperor has commanded your destruction!
皇帝已经下令摧毁你们！
DALEK: Why? Why? Why?
为什么。。。?
DOCTOR: Well, your friends are fighting for you!
看, 你的朋友们正在为你们战斗！
DALEK: Friends?
朋友？
DOCTOR: Down there. Help them.
就在那儿, 去帮他们
DALEK: Friends.
朋友
DALEK: Exterminate! Annihilate them!
终结！灭了他们！
EMPEROR: Danger! This is your Emperor speaking! There is danger here! Obey me!
告急！这里是你们的皇帝在讲话！这里告急！听我的命令！
EMPEROR: Do not fight in here! Do not fight in here! I said, Obey! Obey!
不要在这里战斗！不要在这里战斗！我说过了, 服从！服从！
EMPEROR: Obey me! Obey me!
服从我, 服从我！
EMPEROR: Your Emperor is ordering you. Do not fight in here!
Do not fight in here! Obey!
你们的皇帝命令你们。不要在这里战斗！不要在这里战斗！服从！
EMPEROR: I am your Emperor! Daleks, obey me! Obey! Obey! Obey!
我是你们的皇帝！Dalek, 服从我！服从！服从！
DALEKS: You will be exterminated! All exterminated. Annihilated!
You will all be exterminated! Annihilated!
你们会被终结！全部终结, 灭绝！你们会被终结！灭绝！
EMPEROR: THE DALEK RACE WILL DIE OUT COMPLETELY!
Obey your Emperor! Obey! Ob...
Dalek 种族会被全部灭亡了！服从你们的皇帝, 服从！
(Kemel, Victoria and Jamie are resting in the tunnel,
out side the city.)
（Kemel, Victoria 和 Jamie 在隧道内休息, 他们已经在 Dalek之城的外面了）
(They see someone coming.)
（他们看到有个人过来了）
MAXTIBLE: Kemel! Come here!
Kemel, 过来!
MAXTIBLE: Kill! Kill! Kill! Kill!
DALEK: Attention! Attention! Emergency! Emergency!
All Daleks return to control immediately!
注意, 注意！紧急状况, 紧急！所有 Dalek 立刻回到控制中心！
(Maxtible hurries back to the city.)
（Maxtible 赶紧回到 Dalek之城）
VICTORIA: Poor Kemel!
可怜的 Kemel!
(The Doctor stands watching from the control room entrance.)
（博士站在控制室的入口, 观察着）
(Pieces of the Emperor begin to break away as he is shot at.)
（皇帝被击中了, 他和连接他的线缆部分被炸成了碎片）
(The Doctor runs towards the ___ opening.)
（博士跑向入口）
MAXTIBLE: The Daleks must not... cannot be destroyed.
The race will survive! The Daleks will live! And Rule! FOR EVER!
Dalek 绝不能。。不可能被毁灭。这个种族会长存！ Dalek 会活着, 还要统治！永远！
(The Doctor escapes through the FIXME)
（博士从FIXME里逃了出去）
(One by one the Dalek buildings explode.)
（Dalek之城的建筑一个接一个地爆炸了）
JAMIE: Doctor.
博士
DOCTOR: Jamie! Jamie!
JAMIE: A Dalek nearly caught us, but I... I tossed it over the edge. But... poor Kemel.
有个 Dalek 差点抓到了我们, 但我。。把它扔到悬崖外去了。只是。。。可怜的 Kemel
DOCTOR: Kemel?
JAMIE: Aye. You see, he was trying...
是, 你看, 他是想。。。
VICTORIA: Where is my father?
我父亲在哪里？
VICTORIA: Is... is he dead?
他。。。他死了吗？
DOCTOR: Yes. Yes, I'm afraid he is.
是的, 恐怕是这样。
DOCTOR: But, he didn't die in vain.
I think we have seen the end of the Daleks, forever!
不过, 他并没有白死。我想我们已经见到了 Dalek 的终结, 永远没有了！
DOCTOR: Jamie, we must move along to the TARDIS. It's over there.
Jamie, 我们必须赶去 TARDIS 了, 它在那儿
JAMIE: We can't leave her alone, Doctor.
我们不能单独撇下她, 博士
DOCTOR: We're not going to leave her. She's coming with us!
我们不会撇下她, 她跟我们一起走
DOCTOR: The end. The final end!
结束了, 最终的结局
DALEK: Destroy! Destroy!
摧毁！摧毁！
(Among the dead Daleks, one Dalek is still emitting a pulsating light.)
（在那些死亡的 Daleks 中,有一个 Dalek 的顶灯还在一闪一闪）